Guide to the Zales N. Ecton Papers 1947-1953
Montana State University-Bozeman Library
Zales N. Ecton Papers
1947-1953
Montana State University Library, Merrill G. Burlingame Special Collections P.O. Box 173320 Bozeman, MT 59717-3320 United States Phone (406) 994-4242 Fax (406) 994-2851 http://www.lib.montana.edu/archives/ University Archivist spcoll@www.lib.montana.edu
Collection 1069, MtBC, us
Ecton, Zales N. (Zales Nelson), 1898-1961
15 linear feet
The Zales N. Ecton Papers contains information pertaining to Ecton's position as a U.S. Senator. In general, the collection covers political issues from 1947-1953 at a state and national level. The topics range from correspondence, reclamation, communism and socialism, agriculture and the Brannon plan, and political opposition.
Biographical Note
Zales N. Ecton, born in Iowa April 1, 1898, moved to Montana at age nine. He received his public education in the local schools. After graduation, he attended Montana State College. When the country entered World War 1, Ecton volunteered for training in the Student Army Training Corps. After the war, Ecton completed his education at the University of Chicago Law School. Ecton entered politics in 1932, running for office as a State Representative from Gallatin County. He served in the Montana House of Representatives for four years and in the Montana Senate for ten years. From 1947-1953, Ecton was a U.S. Senator, the first Republican elected by popular vote in Montana. As a Senator, Ecton served on the Senate Appropriations Committee, the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs, the Committee on the United States Post Office and Civil Service, and the Committee on Public Lands. Ecton lost the 1952 election to Mike Mansfield. He returned to Montana and resided in Bozeman until his death in 1961.
The Ecton Collection contains information pertaining to Ecton's position as a U.S. Senator. Within this collection are eighteen series that follow closely to the original order put together by Ecton and his staff. The contents section and the series description of this finding aid provides a more thorough breakdown of each series. In general, the collection covers political issues at a state and national level. The topics range from correspondence, reclamation, communism and socialism, agriculture and the Brannon plan, and political opposition. There is also information dealing with other important governmental figures of the time: Senator Joseph McCarthy, General Douglas MacArthur, and others. The collection offers an overview of political history from 1947-1953.
Series 1 Correspondence, 1947-1953
Series 2 Office Personnel and Office Space, 1947-1952
Series 3 Invitations, 1947-1952
Series 4 Congressional Records, 1949-1952
Series 5 Federal Issues, 1948-1952
Series 6 Agriculture and Natural Resources,1948-1952
Series 7 Valley Authorities, 1947-1952
Series 8 Republican Party Material, 1947-1952
Series 9 Republican Party--Montana, 1948-1952
Series 10 Montana, 1948-1952
Series 11 Mike Mansfield, 1948-1952
Series 12 Native Americans, 1948-1952
Series 13 Communism and Socialism, 1948-1952
Series 14 Government Men, 1948-1952
Series 15 General Information, 1948-1952
Series 16 Scrap Collection, 1948-1952
Series 17 Photographs
Series 18 Scrapbook Collection
This collection is open for research.
Mrs. Zales Ecton, Sr. donated Senator Zales N. Ecton's political files, covering his term as a U.S. Senator (1947-1953), in the spring of 1969.
MacArthur, Douglas, 1880-1964; McCarthy, Joseph, 1908-1957
United States-Congress-Senate
Montana-Politics and government-20th century; United States-Politics and government-1945-1953
Agriculture and state-United States; Communism; Reclamation of land-Government policy-United States; Socialism; Legislators-United States
Agriculture; Civic Activism; Montana; Photographs; Scrapbooks
- Correspondence, 1947-1953; Series 1
  The correspondence was mainly between Senator Ecton, his office staff, and constituents in Montana. The topics ranged from reclamation, communism, atomic energy, and a host of other political concerns. Generally, Ecton responded to each letter, and the response and the original letter are within the same file. The order of this series is chronological and alphabetical within each corresponding year except 1953, where all correspondence is in one file. Also, the correspondence in 1947 does include some correspondence from 1946.
  - A, 1947 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - B, 1947 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - C, 1947 (Box-folder 1/3-4)
  - D, E, 1947 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - F, 1947 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - G, 1947 (Box-folder 1/7-8)
  - H, 1947 (Box-folder 1/9-10)
  - I, 1947 (Box-folder 1/11-12)
  - J, 1947 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - K, 1947 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - L, 1947 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - M, 1947 (Box-folder 1/16-17)
  - N, 1947 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - O, 1947 (Box-folder 1/19)
  - P, 1947 (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Q, 1947 (Box-folder 1/21)
  - R, 1947 (Box-folder 1/22-23)
  - S, 1947 (Box-folder 1/24-26)
  - T, 1947 (Box-folder 1/27)
  - V, 1947 (Box-folder 1/28)
  - W, 1947 (Box-folder 1/29-30)
  - Y, Z, 1947 (Box-folder 1/31)
  - A, 1948 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - B, 1948 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - C, 1948 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - D, 1948 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - E, 1948 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - F, 1948 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - G, 1948 (Box-folder 2/7-8)
  - H, 1948 (Box-folder 2/9-11)
  - I, 1948 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - J, K, 1948 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - L, 1948 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - M, 1948 (Box-folder 2/15)
  - N, 1948 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - O, 1948 (Box-folder 2/17)
  - P, 1948 (Box-folder 2/18)
  - R, 1948 (Box-folder 2/19)
  - S, 1948 (Box-folder 2/20-21)
  - T, 1948 (Box-folder 2/22)
  - W, 1948 (Box-folder 2/23)
  - Y, Z, 1948 (Box-folder 2/24)
  - A, 1949 (Box-folder 2/25)
  - B, 1949 (Box-folder 2/26)
  - C, 1949 (Box-folder 2/27)
  - D, 1949 (Box-folder 2/28)
  - E, 1949 (Box-folder 2/29)
  - F, 1949 (Box-folder 2/30)
  - G, 1949 (Box-folder 2/31)
  - H, 1949 (Box-folder 2/32)
  - I, 1949 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - J, 1949 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - K, 1949 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - L, 1949 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - M, 1949 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - N, 1949 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - O, 1949 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - P, 1949 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Q, 1949 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - R, 1949 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - S, 1949 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - T, 1949 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - U, V, W, X, Y, Z, 1949 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - A, 1950 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - B, 1950 (Box-folder 3/15)
  - C, 1950 (Box-folder 3/16)
  - D, 1950 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - E, 1950 (Box-folder 3/18)
  - F, 1950 (Box-folder 3/19)
  - G, 1950 (Box-folder 3/20)
  - H, 1950 (Box-folder 3/21)
  - I, 1950 (Box-folder 3/22)
  - J, 1950 (Box-folder 3/23)
  - K, 1950 (Box-folder 3/24)
  - L, 1950 (Box-folder 3/25)
  - M, 1950 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - N, 1950 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - O, 1950 (Box-folder 4/3)
  - P, Q, 1950 (Box-folder 4/4)
  - R, 1950 (Box-folder 4/5)
  - S, 1950 (Box-folder 4/6)
  - T, 1950 (Box-folder 4/7)
  - U, V, W, 1950 (Box-folder 4/8)
  - X, Y, Z, 1950 (Box-folder 4/9)
  - A, 1951 (Box-folder 4/10)
  - B, 1951 (Box-folder 4/11)
  - C, 1951 (Box-folder 4/12)
  - D, 1951 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - E, 1951 (Box-folder 4/14)
  - F, 1951 (Box-folder 4/15)
  - G, 1951 (Box-folder 4/16)
  - H, 1951 (Box-folder 4/17)
  - I, 1951 (Box-folder 4/18)
  - J, 1951 (Box-folder 4/19)
  - K, 1951 (Box-folder 4/20)
  - L, 1951 (Box-folder 5/1)
  - M, 1951 (Box-folder 5/2-3)
  - N, 1951 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - O, 1951 (Box-folder 5/5)
  - P, 1951 (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Q, R, 1951 (Box-folder 5/7)
  - S, 1951 (Box-folder 5/8)
  - T, 1951 (Box-folder 5/9)
  - U, V, 1951 (Box-folder 5/10)
  - W, 1951 (Box-folder 5/11)
  - X, Y, Z, 1951 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - A, 1952 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - B, 1952 (Box-folder 5/14-16)
  - C, 1952 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - D, 1952 (Box-folder 6/2)
  - E, 1952 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - F, 1952 (Box-folder 6/4)
  - G, 1952 (Box-folder 6/5)
  - H, 1952 (Box-folder 6/6-8)
  - I, 1952 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - J, 1952 (Box-folder 6/10)
  - K, 1952 (Box-folder 6/11)
  - L, 1952 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - M, 1952 (Box-folder 7/2-3)
  - N, 1952 (Box-folder 7/4)
  - O, 1952 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - P, 1952 (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Q, 1952 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - R, 1952 (Box-folder 7/8)
  - S, 1952 (Box-folder 7/9-11)
  - T, 1952 (Box-folder 7/12)
  - U, V, 1952 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - W, 1952 (Box-folder 8/2-4)
  - X, Y, Z, 1952 (Box-folder 8/5)
  - All, 1953 (Box-folder 8/6)
- Office Personnel and Office Space, 1947-1952; Series 2
  This series covers details regarding Office Personnel and Office Space. Some of the correspondence includes individuals applying for a position on Ecton's staff. Other correspondence is between Ecton and staff members along with correspondence between staff members in Washington D.C. and staff members in Montana. The information encompassing Office Space generally follows the needs of setting up an office--renting and purchasing the necessary items for an office.
  - Office Personnel, 1947 (Box-folder 8/7-8)
  - Office Personnel, 1948 (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Office Personnel, 1949 (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Office Personnel, 1950 (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Office Personnel, 1951 (Box-folder 8/12)
  - Office Personnel, 1952 (Box-folder 8/13)
  - Office Space, 1947 (Box-folder 8/14)
  - Office Space, 1948 (Box-folder 8/15)
  - Office Space, 1949 (Box-folder 8/16)
  - Office Space, 1950 (Box-folder 8/17)
  - Office Space, 1951 (Box-folder 8/18)
  - Office Space, 1952 (Box-folder 8/19)
- Invitations, 1947-1952; Series 3
  This series includes invitations received by Senator Ecton during his term as a federal senator. His constituents in Montana often invited Ecton to attend a variety of functions. Serving in the capacity of a federal senator, Ecton also received many invitations centered around national interests. Those in charge of reclamation projects and military development occasionally asked Ecton to review the progress. Ecton also received an invitation to a dinner sponsored by Albert Einstein in an effort to clear the accusations of the un-American like conduct of Edward U. Condon.
  - 1947 (Box-folder 9/1-5)
  - 1948 (Box-folder 9/6-15)
  - 1949 (Box-folder 9/16-20)
  - 1949 (Box-folder 10/1-2)
  - 1950 (Box-folder 10/3-4)
  - 1951 (Box-folder 10/5-6)
  - 1952 (Box-folder 10/7-8)
- Congressional Records, 1949-1952; Series 4
  This series is simply a collection of Congressional Records and covers a variety of issues brought before the congress between 1949 and 1952.
  - 1949 (Box-folder 11/1-2)
  - 1950 (Box-folder 11/3-5)
  - 1951 (Box-folder 11/6-9)
  - 1951 (Box-folder 12/1-4)
  - 1952 (Box-folder 12/5-8)
- Federal Issues, 1948-1952; Series 5
  This series is a compilation of political issues, ranging from state affairs, national affairs, and international affairs. Some of the files are specific to Ecton's activities in Washington D.C., yet other files include a summary of the Hiss Trial, federal finances, and many other political concerns during Ecton's time in Washington D.C.
  - Taft-Hartley Act (Box-folder 13/1)
  - Reorganization Plans, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 13/2)
  - Public Work Funds Granted, 1947-1952 (Box-folder 13/3)
  - Projects, 1947-1952 (Box-folder 13/4)
  - Civilian Nominations, Montana, since, 1947 (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Republican Administration Assistants and Executive Secretaries Association (Box-folder 13/6)
  - Related Bills (Box-folder 13/7)
  - Patronage (Box-folder 13/8)
  - Interior and Insular Affairs (Box-folder 13/9)
  - Harvey Machine Company--John P. Saylor (Box-folder 13/10)
  - The Hiss Trial--Mundt (Box-folder 13/11)
  - MacArthur's Cleveland Address (Box-folder 13/12)
  - Why Prices Are High--Sanborn-Ecton (Box-folder 13/13)
  - Repeal of Oleomargine Taxes--Ecton (Box-folder 13/14)
  - Government by Law, Not by Men--Ecton (Box-folder 13/15)
  - Why Tax the Cost of Sickness--Ecton (Box-folder 13/16)
  - The Great Question before Senate--Ecton (Box-folder 13/17)
  - Ecton Activities, 1947-1952 (Box-folder 13/18)
  - Congressional Speeches--Ecton (Box-folder 13/19)
  - Ecton Bills (except Indian Bills), 80th, 81st, 82nd Congresses (Box-folder 13/20)
  - Ecton Votes for Reduced Appropriations, 80th-82nd Congresses (Box-folder 13/21)
  - Washington Office Cases--Ecton (Box-folder 13/22-23)
  - Repeal of McCarran Internal Security Act (Box-folder 14/1)
  - Funds--Treasury and Post Office Departments (Box-folder 14/2)
  - Party Platforms (Box-folder 14/3)
  - Veterans (Box-folder 14/4)
  - Senator George D. Aiken (Box-folder 14/5)
  - 81st and 82nd Congresses (Box-folder 14/6)
  - Federal Finance (Box-folder 14/7)
  - Finance--Mainly Ecton (Box-folder 14/8-9)
  - Federal Finance (Box-folder 14/10)
  - Federal Finance (Box-folder 15/1)
  - Foreign Affairs (Box-folder 15/2-3)
  - Dr. Manfred Zapp--Germany (Box-folder 15/4)
  - Foreign Policy (Box-folder 15/5-6)
  - The Korean Crisis--Taft (Box-folder 15/7)
  - News Bulletins, 1951 (Box-folder 15/8-10)
  - News Bulletins, 1952 (Box-folder 15/11-13)
- Agriculture and Natural Resources, 1948-1952; Series 6
  This series contains some information regarding the Brannon Plan, and correspondence between Ecton and his constituents related to the Brannon Plan. Additional information discusses natural resources and the importance of natural resources for the future of the country
  - Agriculture-Brannon Plan--Correspondence (Box-folder 16/1-4)
  - Agriculture-Brannon Plan (Box-folder 16/5)
  - Agriculture--General (Box-folder 16/6-8)
  - Defense Mobilization and Price Control (Box-folder 16/9-11)
  - StockPile Report--Nation's Resources (Box-folder 16/12)
  - Resources for Freedom (Box-folder 16/13)
- Valley Authorities, 1947-1952; Series 7
  This series mainly deals with Valley Authorities, including the Missouri Valley Authority and Columbia Valley Authority. Some files include correspondence concerning the Valley Authorities. Valley Authority bills and power utilities are also part of this series along with a statement from Harold Ickes and Floyd Dominy's resume.
  - M.V.A., 1947 (Box-folder 17/1)
  - M.V.A., 1948 (Box-folder 17/2-4)
  - M.V.A., 1949 (Box-folder 17/5-9)
  - M.V.A., 1950 (Box-folder 17/10)
  - C.V.A., 1949 (Box-folder 17/11)
  - C.V.A., 1950 (Box-folder 17/12)
  - V.A.--Correspondence, 1949 (Box-folder 17/13)
  - V.A.--Correspondence, 1949 (Box-folder 17/14)
  - V.A.--Correspondence, 1950 (Box-folder 17/15)
  - V.A., 1950-1951 (Box-folder 17/16)
  - V.A. Bills (Box-folder 18/1)
  - V.A. General (Box-folder 18/2-4)
  - V.A. Memorandums (Box-folder 18/5-6)
  - Statement of Harold L. Ickes--C.V.A. (Box-folder 18/7)
  - Bureau of Reclamation--Floyd E. Dominy (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Power Utilities--Montana Power (Box-folder 18/9-11)
  - Power Utilities (Box-folder 18/12-14)
- Republican Party Material, 1947-1952; Series 8
  This series contains a variety of information dealing with the Republican Party mainly at a National level. Speech material and campaign issues are part of this series, including Ecton's "The Meaning of Things"--a collection of papers written by Ecton, explaining his perspective of the state of affairs. Part of this series also details Republican activity in certain committees, which generally deals with their opposition, the Democrats.
  - Republican Convention, 1947 (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Republican Campaign, 1948 (Box-folder 19/2-17)
  - Republican Campaign, 1949 (Box-folder 19/18)
  - Republican Campaign, 1950 (Box-folder 19/19-20)
  - Republican Campaign, 1951 (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Republican Campaign, 1952 (Box-folder 20/2)
  - Republican Speech Material, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 20/3)
  - Republican Speech Material, 1949 (Box-folder 20/4-5)
  - Republican Speech Material, 1950 (Box-folder 20/6)
  - Republican Speech Material, 1951 (Box-folder 20/7-8)
  - Republican Propaganda (Box-folder 21/1)
  - News Release, 1948 (Box-folder 21/2)
  - News Release, 1949 (Box-folder 21/3)
  - "The Meaning of Things"--Ecton, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 21/4)
  - "The Meaning of Things"--Ecton, 1952 (Box-folder 21/5)
  - Redbook Our Worst Congressmen--Ecton (Box-folder 21/6)
  - Ecton Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 21/7)
  - Material for Ecton's Senator Pamphlet (Box-folder 21/8)
  - Democratic Corruption (Box-folder 21/9-12)
  - Minority Committee (Box-folder 22/1-6)
  - Resolutions Committee (Box-folder 22/7)
  - Republican Senatorial Committee, 1949 (Box-folder 22/8)
  - Republican Senatorial Committee, 1950 (Box-folder 22/9)
  - Appropriations Committee (Box-folder 22/10)
  - Committee Assignments, 1950 (Box-folder 22/11)
  - Committee Assignments, 1951 (Box-folder 22/12)
  - Republican National Committee (Box-folder 22/13)
- Republican Party--Montana, 1948-1952; Series 9
  This series generally deals with the Republican Party in Montana and the campaign efforts involving Senator Ecton. Some of the files include information concerning committee members in Montana and their work regarding Ecton's campaign. Other files contain speeches made in Montana during Ecton's visits along with his itinerary. There is also general information regarding advertising and broadcasting.
  - Republican State Central Committee (Box-folder 23/1)
  - Montana Republican Committee men and women (Box-folder 23/2)
  - Republican County Chairmen, Committee men, and committee women (Box-folder 23/3)
  - Campaign's Key Men (Box-folder 23/4)
  - Tabulation--Selected Election Returns (Box-folder 23/5)
  - Ecton--Sectional Organization (Box-folder 23/6)
  - Speeches to Montanans--Happenings in Washington (Box-folder 23/7)
  - Campaign Speeches--Montana (Box-folder 23/8-9)
  - Ecton Speeches Montana and Others (Box-folder 23/10-11)
  - Ecton for Senator Club (Box-folder 24/1)
  - Campaign Letters and Wires (Box-folder 24/2-3)
  - Ecton Campaign (Box-folder 24/4-6)
  - Contributions (Box-folder 24/7)
  - Campaign Contributions (Box-folder 24/8)
  - Broadcasting--Montana (Box-folder 25/1)
  - Advertising and Publicity (Box-folder 25/2-5)
  - Itinerary (Box-folder 25/6-7)
  - League of Women Voters (Box-folder 26/1)
  - Address to Women's Republican Club at Butte, 1951 (Box-folder 26/2)
  - People Requesting Favors from Ecton (Box-folder 26/3-4)
  - Thank You Letters--Endorsements During Campaign (Box-folder 26/5)
  - Co-operation Other Organizations (Box-folder 26/6-7)
  - Plans and Staff Instructions, 1952 (Box-folder 26/8)
  - Opposition Activities (Box-folder 26/9-10)
- Montana, 1948-1952; Series 10
  This series mainly contains a list of individuals, performing various occupations in Montana, such as the sheepmen's' list, physicians' list, etc. Rules of Senate and House for Montana are also part of this series--1933, 1935, 1937, 1939, 1941.
  - Montana Labor Protest (Box-folder 27/1)
  - Montana Events (Box-folder 27/2)
  - Directory PMA Committeemen, Montana, 1952 (Box-folder 27/3)
  - Ministers' List--Montana (Box-folder 27/4)
  - VFW List--Montana (Box-folder 27/5)
  - Postal Clerks' List--Montana (Box-folder 27/6)
  - Librarians' List--Montana (Box-folder 27/7)
  - Physicians' List--Montana (Box-folder 27/8)
  - Lawyers' List and Some County Employees--Montana (Box-folder 27/9)
  - Labor Unions' List (Box-folder 27/10)
  - Government Employees--Montana (Box-folder 27/11)
  - Sheepmen's' List--Montana (Box-folder 27/12)
  - Civic Organizations (Box-folder 27/13)
  - Bankers' List--Montana (Box-folder 27/14)
  - American Legion List (Box-folder 27/15)
  - Rules of Senate and House, Montana, 1933; 1935; 1937 (Box-folder 27/16)
  - Rules of Senate and House, Montana, 1939; 1941 (Box-folder 27/17)
- Mike Mansfield, Series 11
  This series mainly contains Mansfield's voting records, remarks, and legislation through 1948-1952. Ecton collected this data in preparation for his campaign against Mansfield in the 1952 election. Mansfield defeated Ecton.
  - Mike Mansfield--General (Box-folder 28/1)
  - Mansfield--China (Box-folder 28/2)
  - Mansfield's Voting Record--80th Congress, 1st session (Box-folder 28/3)
  - Mansfield's Voting Record--80th Congress, 2nd session (Box-folder 28/4)
  - Mansfield's Remarks and Legislation--80th Congress, 1st Session (Box-folder 28/5)
  - Mansfield's Remarks and Legislation--80th Congress, 2nd Session (Box-folder 28/6)
  - Mansfield's Voting Record--81st Congress, 1st session (Box-folder 28/7)
  - Mansfield's Voting Record--81st Congress, 2nd session (Box-folder 28/8)
  - Mansfield's Remarks--81st Congress, 1st Session (Box-folder 28/9)
  - Mansfield's Remarks and Legislation--81st Congress, 1st Session (Box-folder 28/10)
  - Mansfield's Remarks--81st Congress, 2nd Session (Box-folder 28/11)
  - Mansfield's Remarks and Legislation--81st Congress, 2nd Session (Box-folder 28/12)
  - Mansfield's Voting Record--82nd Congress, 1st session (Box-folder 28/13)
  - Mansfield's Voting Record--82nd Congress, 2nd session (Box-folder 28/14)
  - Mansfield's Remarks--82nd Congress, 1st Session (Box-folder 28/15)
  - Mansfield's Remarks and Legislation--82nd Congress, 1st Session (Box-folder 28/16)
  - Mansfield's Remarks--82nd Congress, 2nd Session (Box-folder 28/17)
  - Mansfield's Remarks and Legislation--82nd Congress, 2nd Session (Box-folder 28/18)
  - Voting Record--Mansfield (Box-folder 29/1)
  - Voting Record--82nd Congress, 1st Session (Box-folder 29/2)
  - Voting Record--82nd Congress, 2nd Session (Box-folder 29/3)
  - Voting Record--General (Box-folder 29/4)
- Native Americans, Series 12
  This series includes files pertaining to tubercular Indians and treatment at Galen Hospital. Also in this series are several Bill related to Indian affairs.
  - Galen Hospital for Tubercular Indians (Box-folder 29/5)
  - Indian Affairs (Box-folder 29/6)
  - Indian Bills (Box-folder 29/7)
- Communism and Socialism, Series 13
  This series contains information pertaining to Communism and Socialism. The Republican Party maintained an anti-communism and anti-socialism and most of the information reflects this agenda.
  - Moscow's Master Plan (Box-folder 30/1)
  - U.S. News--Communist Threat (Box-folder 30/2)
  - "True"--George John Dawson--War Surplus and Communist Customers (Box-folder 30/3)
  - Saturday Evening Post--Hiss Case (Box-folder 30/4)
  - Anti-Communism and Socialism (Box-folder 30/5-8)
  - Minority Policy Committee, 1952 (Box-folder 30/9)
- Government Men, 1948-1952; Series 14
  This series includes files regarding Senator McCarthy, Senator Martin, Congressman D'Ewart, and General MacArthur. Each file is specific to the person and contains a variety of information based on their role in the government. For instance, the McCarthy files provide some biographical discussion but also pertain to McCarthy's involvement in the federal government.
  - Senator McCarthy (Box-folder 31/1-3)
  - Senator Martin (Box-folder 31/4-6)
  - Congressman D'Ewart (Box-folder 31/7-8)
  - General MacArthur (Box-folder 31/9)
- General Information, 1948-1952; Series 15
  This series is a collection of general subject materials put together by Ecton and his staff. It ranges from newspaper clippings, speech material, congressional records, and more.
  - General Information (Box-folder 32/1-7)
- Scrap Collection, 1948-1952; Series 16
  This series is mainly newspaper clippings, covering a variety of topics. Some of the files are under specific names, but the content within the file is generally a newspaper clipping about the person, such as the Eisenhower file.
  - Copper and Civilization (Box-folder 33/1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 33/2)
  - Democratic Views (Box-folder 33/3)
  - 81st Congress clippings (Box-folder 33/4)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 33/5)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 33/6)
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower (Box-folder 33/7)
  - Leif Erickson (Box-folder 33/8)
  - Defense (Box-folder 33/9)
  - Robert A. Taft (Box-folder 33/10)
  - Bills (Box-folder 33/11)
  - Henry J. Taylor (Box-folder 33/12)
  - Harry S. Truman (Box-folder 33/13)
  - James E. Murray (Box-folder 33/14)
  - Gov. John Bonner (Box-folder 33/15)
  - Bernard Baruch (Box-folder 33/16)
  - Herbert Hoover (Box-folder 33/17)
- Photographs, Series 17